Previously on Elementary...
Uh, we're here to see
Fiona Helbron, aka "Mittens."
We're here to see
She wrote some software
that was used
to take control
of a car last night
that caused a fatal accident.
She wouldn't hurt anybody.
She couldn't.
They say autism is a spectrum,
but it's really an array
of different conditions
all lumped together.
I prefer the term
"neuro-atypical."
What did you
want to say?
Well, I confess
that I'm here to discuss
the uncomfortable subject
of the murders
which occurred the other day.
More specifically, I'd like you
to help me apprehend
the person responsible.
중국 달탐사선이 당신 아버지의
살해시도와 무슨 관련이 있어요?
What does China landing
a moon rover have to do
with someone trying
to kill your father?
내가 알기론, 전혀 없거나
Nothing, as far
as I can tell.
전부겠죠
Or everything.
어느 순간이든
At any given moment,
아버지가 관여하는
영역이 넓기 때문에
father's fingers
were in many pies,
부재시 영향을 받는 대소사를
모두 검토하고 있어요
so I'm reviewing events
both great and small
which might have been
influenced by his removal.
그래서요?
And?
몇개는 가능해요
A few possibilities.
아직 부각된 일은 없지만
Nothing in
high relief, as yet.
짜증나지 않아요
Okay, that's not annoying.
아버지의 개인 주치의가
배에서 꺼낸 총알이에요
These are the bullets
that father's private surgeons
removed &wom abdomen.
이제 모든 정보를 공유하기 때문에
Now that we're all
sharing information,
보내달라고 요구했어요
I requested that
they send them over.
아버지에게 과보수를 받는 수사관들은
His overpaid investigators
were making
증거수집을 전혀 하지 않았어요
zero progress with them,
after all.
당신은 했어요?
And you have?
범인 추적에 별로 소용이 없어요
They're of little use
in tracking his shooters.
9밀리, 할로우포인트, 미국제
Nine-millimeter,
hollow point, American-made.
세계 어디에서나 구할 수 있어요
Obtainable almost anywhere
in the world.
하지만 아버지를 살해하려는 자의
마음을 아는데 도움이 돼요
They do however,
help me enter the mind
of whoever might have wanted
to murder my father.
길게 가진 않아요
Not a long walk, I confess.
어디 가요?
You going somewhere?
네, 피오나 헬브론 기억해요?
Yeah, do you remember
Fiona Helbron?
I do.
네
탐정이 필요하대요
Well, apparently,
she's in need of a detective.
She e-mailed me yesterday,
and asked me to meet up.
어제 이메일을 보내서
만나자고 했어요
당신만요?
Just you?
나만요
Just me.
사회적 상호작용이
피오나에게 힘드니까
You know, social interactions
are tough for her,
셋은 복잡하겠다 싶어서요
so I'm guessing three's a crowd.
나중에 알려줄게요
I'll circle back later.
경감님
Captain?
Sherlock Holmes,
셜록 홈즈
Captain Will Lombardi,
Narcotics.
마약반의 윌 롬바르디 경감이야
얘기 많이 들었어요
I've heard a lot about you.
걱정해야되나요?
Should I be concerned?
저번에 다른 서의
경찰을 불렀을 때
Last time you summoned
me to meet police
살인 혐의를 받아서요
from another precinct,
they accused me of murder.
안심해도 돼. 윌은 오랜 친구야
You can relax.
Will's an old friend.
어제 같이 저녁을 먹었는데
The two of us were out
having dinner last night,
윌의 팀이 가진 문제에 대해 말했어
and Will mentioned a problem
that his team is having.
막힌 일이 있대
Something that stumped them.
내가 너한테 말하라고 했어
I told him he should
talk to you.
그래요
Yeah.
"사탄의 아이들"이라고 들어봤어요?
You ever heard
of "Satan's Brood?"
네, 오토바이 폭주족으로
Yeah, motorcycle gang.
시내외의 대량의 필로폰
유통 혐의를 받고 있죠
In charge of a sizeable share
of the crystal meth distribution
in and around the city.
맞아요, 나쁜 놈들이죠
Yeah, these are bad guys.
완전무장을 하고
Armed to the teeth.
퀸즈의 요새같이 만든
빌딩을 근거지로 해요
They operate out
of a building in Queens
that they protect
like a fortress.
그럼 제가 뭘 도와드릴까요?
And how can I be of service?
강탈을 해내고 싶어요
We want to pull
off a heist.
-강탈
-그들의 빌딩에서
A heist.
At their building.
바이크를 타는 사탄주의자들이 완전무장으로
You want to steal something
from a heavily armed,
필로폰을 거래하는 곳에서
뭘 가져오라고요?
meth-dealing band
of bike-riding Satanists?
Interested?
관심있어요?
완전 짜릿해요
I'm practically engorged.
언제 시작할까요?
When do we start?
♪ Elementary 4x12 ♪
A View With a Room
Original Air Date on February 11, 2016
??Elementary 4x12 ??/font>
A View With a Room
Original Air Date on February 11, 2016
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
?? ??
Taking this place
would be a piece of cake
여길 접수하는 건 소규모
군대로도 쉬운 일이지
for a small army.
클리셰의 답습에 비용을
아끼지 않는군요
Well, they've
spared no expense
embracing the clich챕s,
have they?
아주 흔한 가죽옷
Ubiquitous leather,
최대 소음발생 바이크
the bikes modified
for maximum noise.
38구경과 개조 산탄총을 잊었군
And you forgot the .38s
and the sawed-off shotguns.
보이는 게 다가 아니지
But it's not just show
with these guys.
미주리 남부에서
물건을 나르기도 해
They also shuttle product
in from Southern Missouri.
5개의 주에서 경찰들이
체포하려했지만
Now, they've had run-ins with
cops in five different states,
쉽게 잡히지가 않아
and never once did
they go down easy.
이 친구가 윌의 위장경찰,
This is Will's undercover guy,
라이언 더닝 형사야
Detective Ryan Dunning.
카멜레온 같아요
Quite the chameleon.
12개월동안 놈들에게
필로폰을 사면서
For 12 months,
he's been buying
crystal from them,
소량에서 하프파운드까지 늘었어
working up from grams
to half-pounds.
이제 형사를 마약상이라고 확신을 줬어요
So he's convinced them
he's a dealer.
여기 있는 모든 정보를
더닝이 가져온거지
Right, all the Intel
you see here came from him.
그럼 강탈의 목표는 뭡니까?
And what's the target
of the heist?
더닝은 뉴욕 지역 두목인
Dunning is in tight
니콜라스 패리스와는 친하지않아
with the New York leader,
Nicholas Farris.
예리하고 조직적이지
Yeah, he's sharp,
and he's organized.
더닝 말로는 모든 거래기록을
컴퓨터에 기록한대
According to Dunning,
he keeps records
of the whole operation
on his computer.
건물 뒷쪽의 사무실로
Right, which is in an office
rear of the building,
-굽어진 통로 옆
-정답이야
up a ramp.
Correct.
더닝이 맞고,
우리가 컴퓨터를 얻으면
If Dunning's right,
and we can get that,
유통망, 판매책,
은행계좌를 알 수 있고
then we get the supply chain,
foot soldiers, bank accounts,
유죄선고도 자유자재로 할 수 있지
we can make convictions
up and down the ladder.
그럼 아까 얘기했던
'소규모 군대'로 급습하면 될텐데요
So why don't you
just raid the place
with this "small army"
that you mentioned?
'더닝이 맞다면', 말이지
I said, "If Dunning is right."
이 놈들은 자기 물건을 좋아해
See, these guys like
their own product.
자지 않아
They never sleep.
그래서 실제로 컴퓨터를
확인하지는 못했어
So Dunning's never had a chance
to actually check the computer.
그래서 급습하지 않고
내용을 확인할 수는 없다
So you can't confirm
its contents
without storming the castle.
급습하면, 놈들은 지울것이고
If you storm the castle,
and it's empty,
1년의 노력은 물거품이 되겠죠
you've wasted a year's work.
진퇴양난이네
Catch-22.
확실히 하자면, 컴퓨터
자체를 원하는 건 아냐
And let me be clear,
we are not trying
to get the whole machine.
더닝이 들어가서 복사를
하고 무사히 빠져나올
We just need enough time
for Dunning to get in there,
copy the files
onto a thumb drive
시간이 필요할 뿐이야
and get out with his head
still attached.
그래서 내용을 분석할 수 있도록
So you can analyze
its contents,
쉬워보이는군요
Straightforward enough.
Is it?
그래?
우리 애들이 몇주동안 애썼어
My people have been working
on this for weeks.
그럼 그 전에 오시지 그랬어요
Well, then you should have come
to see me weeks ago.
??To say you're trying... ??
Fiona, hi.
You're late.
-피오나, 안녕하세요
-늦었어요
Three minutes. I'm sorry.
3분, 미안해요
당신이 늦어서, 코드를
만들기 시작했어요
Because you were late,
I started working on some code.
-괜찮아요
-시작했으니까
That's okay.
Because I started,
끝까지 해야해요
now I need to finish.
I'll get some coffee.
커피 가져올게요
끝났어요
I'm finished.
How have you been?
어떻게 지냈어요?
잘 지냈어요, 고마워요
I've been well, thank you.
How have you been?
새로운 상사가 와요
이름은 그렉 와키노
I have a new boss.
His name is Greg Wakino.
He might be a criminal.
범죄자가 틀림없어요
What makes you think that?
왜 그렇게 생각해요?
이전 상사가 범죄자였어요
My last boss was a criminal.
I remember,
you helped us prove that.
기억해요. 증명하는 걸 도와줬었죠
하지만 대부분의 사람들은
범죄자가 아니에요
But most people
are not criminals.
이전 상사는 내 코드로
사람들을 다치게했고
My last boss
used my code to hurt people,
and I just can't
let that happen again.
똑같은 일은 용납할 수 없어요
그래서 그렉 와키노가
좋은 사람인지 알아야해요
So I need to know
if Greg Wakino is a good person.
배경조사를 해주길 원해요?
Do you want me to run
a background check on him?
돈은, 많이 있어요
For money.
I have lots of it.
펜틸리온은 내가 쓰는 것보다
더 많은 돈을 주기 때문에
Pentillion pays me
more than I spend,
so I can give you
whatever you need.
원하는 만큼 줄 수 있어요
고마워요, 하지만 당신이
나와 셜록의 부탁을 들어줬잖아요
I appreciate it,
but you did me and Sherlock
a favor last time.
이번엔 우리가 도와줄게요
We can do you one
in return.
맞아요. 내 부탁을 들어줄 수 있죠
You're right,
you can do me a favor.
Well, thank you.
고마워요
You're welcome.
천만에요
가져본 적도 없는 3살
여자애를 위해 만들었나봐요
You're finally making up
for that childhood you never had
as a three-year-old girl
"반짝반짝 푸들의 집" 전량을
장난감가게에서 사왔어요
Bought out
a toy shop's entire stock
of "Sparkle Poodle Playhouse""
유니콘은 바이크
The unicorns are the bikes.
기차는 당구대
The train's the pool table.
얘는 두목인 닉
This one is Nick, the leader.
무시무시한 폭주족의 모형에
딱이라고 생각하지 않아요?
I think it captures the gestalt
of a fearsome biker gang,
don't you?
이게 문자로 보냈던 그 사건이에요?
I take it this is the case
you texted me about,
마약반에서 컴퓨터에
담긴 정보의 탈취요?
helping Narcotics get
information off of a computer?
Which is...
그건
the cupcake
안쪽 사무실의 컵케익이죠
in the inner office.
그렇군요
Obviously.
얼마나 진행됐어요?
So, how is it going?
현실적인 문제를
예견할 수가 없어요
Well, it's early, but I can't
foresee any real problems.
위장잠입 중인 더닝 형사와
직접 만나자고 했어요
I've requested an in-person
meeting with Detective Dunning,
the department's
undercover operative.
대부분 숨겨진 카메라를
차고 있었지만
He's been wearing
a concealed camera
for most of the year,
빠진 부분을 알고 싶어서요
but there are some holes
in his intelligence
I would like to fill.
마약상으로 위장중인 경찰의
Given the
communication restraints
연락제한으로 인해
of an officer posing
as a drug dealer,
언제 만나게 될지는
말하기 힘들어요
it's difficult to say when I'm
going to be hearing from him.
피오나는 어땠어요?
How's our friend, Fiona?
새로 오는 상사에 대해 걱정이라
She's worried
about her new boss,
코드를 공유하기 전에
so she wants to run
a background check
뒷조사를 해주길 원했어요
before she shares code with him.
그럴만도 해요
I don't really blame her.
도와줄까요?
Do you require assistance?
아뇨, 그정도야 뭐
No, it's routine.
I'm to meet Detective Dunning
on Staten Island in one hour.
1시간 후 스테튼 아일랜드에서
더닝 형사를 만나기로 했어요
오래 걸리겠네
That's going to take some doing.
아무 것도 손대지 말아요
Please don't
touch anything.
자제해볼게요
I'll try to
restrain myself.
외딴 곳에서의 접선 장소
선택에 박수를 보낼게요
I applaud your choice in
out-of-the-way meeting places.
당신이 잠입형사라는 걸
전혀 모르겠어요
No chance of those you've
infiltrated spotting us here.
이게 장난인 줄 알아?
You think this is a joke?
폭주족 해산을 위해
목숨을 건 당신에게
You risk your neck
to bring down a violent gang,
보내는 나의 최고의 찬사입니다
you have my utmost respect.
데님 코스플레이 자금
모으려고 열심이던데
They peddle poison to finance
their denim cosplay.
그놈들에게는 조롱만 보낼 뿐이죠
They deserve all
the ridicule I can muster.
롬바르디 경감에게 사진이
더 필요하다고 했다면서
Lombardi said
you needed more photos.
자
There you go.
Thanks.
고마워요
내가 빠지길 원하는군요?
You want no part of me,
do you?
당신 도움 요청하지 않았어
I didn't ask for your help.
이 놈들을 잡아야한다고 말했지
I told Lombardi he should
take this crew down.
You don't share his,
"catch-22" opinion?
진퇴양난이라는 의견은
동의하지 않나요?
No confidence
in the computer's contents?
컴퓨터의 내용물을
신뢰할 수 없다?
알아낼 방법은 하나 있지
I know one way to find out.
어쨌든, 이거면 충분하겠어요
Well, regardless,
these will suffice.
Gonna have to.
잘해봐
난 다시 나오지 않을거야
I'm not doing this again.
뭐야?
What?
이 만남에 다른 목적도 있어요
I had another item
on the agenda for this meeting.
내가 받은 정보의 진짜
구멍은 당신이었어요
The real hole in the information
I was provided, was you.
당신의 신체크기, 손재주
Your physical dimensions,
your dexterity.
가요
You'll do.
가구가 전부 없어진 거 알아요?
You know all the furniture
is gone, right?
옥상에서 만나요
Join me on the roof,
would you?
뭐하는 거예요?
What are you doing?
시험중이죠
Test runs.
사탄의 아이들
침입 계획을 짜야해요
I need to get my plan
for Satan's Brood
on its feet.
더닝 형사가 다른 길을 이용해
To try and get
a sense of how long
갱단의 아지트를 걸을 때
it's gonna take
Detective Dunning
to traverse
the gang's headquarters
얼마나 걸리는지 체험해보려고
using different routes.
Is that my bed?
저거 내 침대죠?
네, 당구대를 대신할
물건이 필요했어요
Yeah, I needed a substitute
for the gang's pool table.
이걸 다 어떻게 했어요?
How did you do all this?
루크 기억해요?
가구 옮겨주는 사람?
Do you remember Luc,
my personal mover?
네
Yeah, well,
빨리 오라고 해요
he better still be up here,
10분후까지 내 방으로
침대를 돌려놓지 않으면
because if my bed
is not back
in my room
in ten minutes...
자물쇠 바꿨어요?
Did you change the lock?
닉 패리스의 방 문에
있는 것과 같아요
It's the same one
that's on the door
of Nick Farris' office.
I'd like you to pick it.
열어봐요
It's unreasonable
to expect Detective Dunning
더닝 형사가 나만큼 날렵할
거라는 예상은 힘들어서
to be as nimble as I am,
당신이 시간을 재는게
최선이라고 생각했어요
so I thought it best
to time you.
휴게실에는 항상 사람이 많다면서
You said the common room
is always crowded,
how's he supposed
to pk a lock
자물쇠 따는 걸 아무도 못 볼까요?
without a bunch
of bikers seeing him?
당연히 주의를 돌려야해요
Obviously,
a distraction will be needed.
다른 범죄자들이 자기 영역에
Nothing infuriates
a territorial gang
침범하는 걸 가장 싫어하기 때문에
more than other criminals
infringing on their territory,
길 건너편의 수표교환소를
노린 강도사건을 꾸며서
so staging a loud holdup
of the check casher's
across the street
밖으로 유인해야해요
should draw people outside.
더닝의 정보로 근거지
부근 스트립 클럽에서
I've also noticed
from Dunning's Intel,
there's a reliable dip
in attendance
수요일 무료 점심 뷔페에
at the gang's headquarters
참석하는 사람이 많다는
믿을만한 점을 발견했어요
that coincides with
the free Wednesday lunch buffet
at the strip club
around the corner.
I mean, we could wait
for the inevitable outbreak
불가피한 A형 간염 전염까지
기다릴 수도 있지만
of hepatitis A,
but I think the detective
형사가 더 빠른 작전을
원한다고 생각해요
might want to act
sooner than that.
Captain,
경감님
Watson and I are just
ironing out a few kinks,
왓슨과 내가 몇가지 바로잡고 있지만
강탈 계획은 곧 완성돼요
but I think the plan
for the heist
is going to be ready shortly.
그래, 수정은 그만해도 돼
Yeah, well you can stop ironing.
이제 더이상 필요 없겠어
We won't be needing it anymore.
왜요?
Why not?
더이상 내부자가 없거든
Because we no longer have
an inside man to carry it out.
라이언 더닝 형사가
Detective Ryan Dunning
죽었어
is dead.
지금 말할 수 있는 건, 더닝이
자기 컴퓨터에 남긴거야
As far as we can tell,
Dunning went after
the computer on his own.
이 영상은 '바디 캠(body cam)'에
있던 저장장치에 있었어
This footage is from the drive
on his body cam.
녹화해야 파일의 출처를
기록할 수 있었을거야
He must've recorded it
so he could document
the source of the files.
더 있어요?
Is there more to the video?
아니
No.
카메라 선이 빠진 것 같아
The wire must have got
pulled out of the camera.
아마 범인이 끌고갔을 때겠지
Probably when the killer
dragged the body away.
경고도 없이 쐈어요
The shooter didn't
issue a warning,
사무실에서 더닝이
뭘 하는지 묻지도 않고
didn't ask Dunning
what he was doing in the office.
조직에서 경찰이란 걸 알았을까요?
Do you think the gang
realized he was a cop?
알았다면 시체를
아예 없앴을 걸요
If they had,
they would've done
a better job getting
rid of the body.
그리고 도청기도 확인하고 없앴을거야
And they sure as hell
would have checked him
for a wire. No.
가장 의심해볼 수 있는 상황은
The best guess is that
they thought he was a dealer,
바가지를 씌우려다가
마약상이라고 생각하고
who was trying to rip them off,
잡혔을 거라는 추측이지
caught him with his hand
in the cookie jar.
바보
Idiot.
뭐라고?
Excuse me?
더닝이요
Dunning.
그 사람 만났어요
I met the man.
조심성이 없었어요, 모험을 즐기고
He was impatient.
A risk-taker.
자살이 아니에요
He wasn't suicidal.
폭주족들의 현황에 대해 제공한
Which, given everything he
shared with us about the gang's
모든 정보로 봐선, 멍청한
시도였다는 설명만이 가능해요
comings and goings, would be
the only other explanation
for this stupid attempt.
기회가 생겼다고
생각했을 수도 있어요
Maybe he thought he saw
a window of opportunity.
전부다 스타워즈를 보러 갔다거나
Maybe they all went to see
그럴 수도 있죠, 우린 모르니까
Star Wars or something,
we don't know.
어쨌든 경찰이 죽었어
Anyway, a cop is dead.
싸울 준비는 됐어
The gloves are off.
동트기 전에 ESU에서 습격했어
ESU hit the hangout before dawn.
20킬로의 필로폰과
14명의 조직원을 잡았지
Netted 20 kilos of meth
and 14 gang members.
정규단원들이었어
That's all of the regulars,
except...
두목만 빼고
the leader.
이름은 닉 패리스
Name is Nick Farris.
긴급수배 중이야
We put a Finest Message
out on him.
Do we know
조직원 중 누가 범인인지 알아요?
which of the gang members
is the shooter?
아니. 아무도 말을 안해
No. No one's talking.
말하지 않겠죠
They won't have to.
총격범을 알아낼 다른 방법이 있어요
There might be another way
to identify the gunman.
여기 소매부분이 올라갔어요
His sleeve rides up here.
오른손목에 있는 점
There's a mole
on his right wrist,
모양이
shaped like...
Iceland.
아이슬란드군요
잡아온 바이커들을
확인해보라고 하지
I'll ask someone to check
the bikers we have in custody.
CSU에서 아직 현장 처리중이죠
I take it CSU
is still processing the scene?
가보고싶어요
I'd like to see it.
데자뷰같이
It's almost like d챕j vu,
진입에 너무 몰두한 나머지
entering a space
you've studied so intently,
들어가지를 않네요
but never set foot in.
더닝 형사의 조사에는
냄새의 습격이 빠져있어요
Although,
Detective Dunning's research
failed to include
the onslaught of smells.
여러 종류의 연기, 체취,
Smoke of several types,
body odor,
알코올, 소비 전후
alcohol,
pre- and post-consumption.
경감님 전화였어요
That was the captain.
구금중인 바이커들을
모두 확인했대요
All the bikers in custody
have been checked out.
흉터와 문신은 많았지만
There's plenty
of scars and tattoos,
아이슬란드 모양의 점은 없었어요
but no one's sporting
a map of Iceland.
닉 패리스가 더닝을 쏜
사람일 수도 있어요
So Nick Farris is probably
the one who shot Dunning.
패리스의 방을 찾아야겠어요
I'm gonna try
to find his office.
필요없어요. 이쪽으로
No need, it's this way.
러그가 없어요
The rug is gone.
총에 맞았을 때 더닝이
그 위로 쓰러졌어요
Dunning landed on
a rug when he was shot.
여기 있던 러그를
벌써 담았어요?
Hey, you guys already bag
a rug that was here?
우리가 왔을때는
바닥에 없었어요
The floor was clear
when we got here.
혈흔과 발사잔여물을 제거하기
위해 범인이 치웠을지도
Likely the killer removed it
to eliminate blood
and gunshot residue.
이 지역의 쓰레기수거를 확인해볼게요
I'll have Unis check all
the Dumpsters in the area.
사라진 닉 패리스를
찾을 곳을 알아낸 것 같아요
I think I might know where
to find the missing Nick Farris.
이건 앤티크 영국제 오토바이인
트라이엄프 650의 부러진 시동장치예요
This is a broken
kick-start lever to
an antique British motorcycle,
Triumph 650.
오는 길에 압수한 바이크들을 봤어요
Well, on our way in,
I saw them
loading the bikes for impound.
내가 보기에 전부 할리 같던데
Looked to me like
they were all Harleys.
15대죠. 조직원 수대로,
닉 패리스의 바이크도 포함해서
15 of them.
One for each member of the gang,
including Nick Farris'.
I recognized his
더닝이 찍은 사진에서 봤어요
from a photograph
that Dunning took of it.
닉 패리스는 없지만
바이크는 있다?
So Nick Farris isn't here,
but his bike is?
급습을 미리 듣고
Maybe he heard
about the raid,
시외로 도망갔을 수도 있어요
got a different ride
out of town.
아니면 다행히도
아직 남아있을지도
Or, if we're lucky,
he still intends to.
4염화에틸렌
Tetrachloroethylene.
특히 꽉 조인 볼트를 풀때 쓰는 기름이죠
It's an oil used to remove
particularly stubborn bolts.
매연으로 볼 때
Judging by the fumes,
이건 떼어낸지 48시간이 안됐어요
this was removed
in the last 48 hours.
바이크 출처가 어디든,
아직 가게에 있겠네요
So whatever bike that's from,
it still might be in the shop.
숙련된 기술자들만이 앤티크
영국 오토바이를 수리할 수 있어요
Only a handful
of mechanics
in the city service
antique British motorcycles.
바이크 가게들은 악명높은
소음을 내고 있으니
Bike shops keep
notoriously lazy hours.
경찰들에게 가게를 수색하도록 하면
If we post police
at each of them,
2번째 애마를 고치러 간
패리스를 잡을 수 있어요
we might get lucky
and catch Mr. Farris
as he picks up
his second ride.
경감님께 보고할게요
I'll let the captain know.
잠깐 나 없어도 괜찮죠?
Hey, are you okay
without me for a while?
피오나를 다시 만나러 가려고요
I'm supposed to meet
with Fiona again.
사라진 바이크가 발견되면 알려줄게요
I'll let you know
if the missing biker turns up.
이건 2년전 발매된 잡지예요
This was published
in a trade magazine
a few years ago.
미화되긴 했지만
It reads like a puff piece,
내 조사 결과를 보면
but if you look at my research,
모두 사실이란 걸 알게 될 거예요
you'll see
that it is all true.
종합해볼때, 그렉 와키노는
Greg Wakino is,
by all accounts,
좋은 사람이에요
a great guy.
영리하고, 신중하고, 훌륭한 리더죠
Smart, patient,
a great leader.
그리고 자선단체 2곳의
이사이기도 해요
He's also on the board
of two charities.
필도 자선단체 일을 했어요
Phil was involved
in charities.
사람들이 훌륭한
사람이라고도 했어요
People called him
a great guy.
필과 그렉은 전혀
다른 사람이에요
Well, he and Greg
are very different people.
내 생각일 뿐이지만
And for what it's worth,
난 좋은 느낌이예요
I get a really good feeling
from him.
도움이 돼요
That helps.
모두 도움이 돼요
All of this helps.
고마워요
Thank you.
'천만에요'라고 해요
Say, "You're welcome."
천만에요
You're welcome.
줄 게 있어요
I'd like you
to take something.
'지혜로운 고양이가 되기 위한 지침서'
(Old Possum's Book of Practical Cats)
Old Possum's Book
of Practical Cats.
토마스 스턴즈 엘리엇 지음
By Thomas Stearns Eliot.
TS라고도 불려요
He was also called "T.S."
1939년
1939.
이건 초판이잖아요
This is a first edition.
피오나 난 못 받아요
Fiona, I can't take this.
이건 너무 귀해요
This is too generous.
제대로 얘기를 못했네요, 미안해요
I wasn't clear, I'm sorry.
셜록에게 전해줬으면 해요
I'd like you
to take it to Sherlock.
셜록의 책이에요.
나한테 빌려줬어요
It's his.
He loaned it to me.
셜록이요?
He did?
경찰이 필을 체포했던 날
The day the police
arrested Phil.
내가 고양이를 좋아한다는 걸 알고
He knew I liked cats,
고양이에 대한 시도
좋아할 거라고 생각했지만
so he thought I might like poems
about them, too.
아니었어요
I didn't.
셜록에게는 말하지 말아요
You don't have to tell him that.
안할게요
I won't.
엉뚱한 사람을 잡았어
You got the wrong guy.
당신이 닉 패리스 맞지?
You are Nick Farris, right?
차고에서 가져가려던
트라이엄프 650도 당신 바이크이고
That was your Triumph 650
you were trying to pick up
at that garage?
내가 하지 않았다는 말이야
I mean, I didn't do this.
손목을 보여주겠나
Do us a favor,
show us your wrist.
뭐라고?
Come again?
오른손목, 보여줘
Your right wrist--
we want to take a look.
점이 없어요
No mole.
무슨 말을 하는거야?
What are you talking about?
어제 클럽하우스에서 14명을 데려왔어
We took down 14 of your buddies
last night at your clubhouse.
내가 알고 싶은 건,
우리가 놓친 사람이 누구지?
What I want to know is,
who did we miss?
아무도 없는 것 같은데
Sounds like nobody.
다른 조직의 바이커나
Any bikers
from another chapter,
다른 주의 손님, 여자 접대부는?
out-of-state guests,
female entertainment?
이미 말했듯이, 난 거기 없었지만
I already told you,
I wasn't there,
우리 애들은 규칙을 다 알아
but my guys know the rules,
손님은 없어
no guests.
그들 중 한명이 한 짓이야
You think
one of them did it,
우리가 아는 건
only we already know,
범인과 일치하는 사람이 없다는거야
none of them is a match
for our shooter.
뭘 말하라는 건지 모르겠네
Then I don't know
what to tell you.
CCS에서 네 컴퓨터를 가져갔어, 알지?
You get that CCS has
your computer now, right?
IT 부대라고 생각하면 돼
They're like
the department's I.T. squad.
구석구석을 뒤지고 있어
They're going to dig
through every nook and cranny.
컴퓨터와 더닝의 비디오로 봐서
Between that and all
the video Dunning got of you,
15년에서 25년형은 받을거야
you're looking at 15 to 25.
Help us find
총격범을 찾는걸 도와주면
the person who did this,
maybe the D.A.
검사가 거래를 제안할수도 있어
offers you a deal.
웃겨?
Is something funny?
생각중이었어
I was just thinking,
경찰과 내가 원하는 게 같은 건
this is the first time
in my life,
내 인생에 처음이거든
me and the cops want
the same thing.
누가 한 짓인지 모르지만
I don't know who did this,
but whoever he is,
누구든
그 놈때문에 내가 잡혔으니
he brought you guys
down on my head, so...
찾길 바라
I hope you find him.
그리고 내 방으로 넣어줘
And I hope you put him
in my cell.
그 놈이랑 할 얘기가 많아
He and I have a lot
to talk about.
That can not be good
for your eyes.
눈에 안 좋을텐데
눈이 거슬려요
Mine eyes offend me.
뭔가 놓쳤어요
They're missing something.
불안한 느낌이죠
It's an unsettling sensation.
마커스의 문자를 받았어요
So, I got Marcus' text.
Farris isn't our shooter.
패리스는 범인이 아니고
어제 잡은 조직원 중 한명이겠죠
Obviously, one of the gang
let someone in last night.
자기들이 아니라고 맹세했어요
They swear that they did not.
난 믿어요
I believe them.
침입자가 있었을까요?
What, you think
someone broke in?
본거지를 거의 침투할 수 없다는
사실을 제외하면, 그렇다고 말해야죠
Leaving aside the fact that
the Brood's lair
is nigh impenetrable,
let's say they had.
체면이 있는데 도둑맞았다고 하겠어요?
What would be their agenda,
to steal from the gang?
아무 것도 도난당하지
않았다고 말하겠죠
As far as anyone can tell,
nothing was taken.
조폭들이 한 일이 아닐 수도 있어요
Maybe the shooting didn't have
anything to do with the gang.
더닝에게 적이 있는데, 미행해서,
Maybe Dunning had an enemy,
they followed him in...
15명의 무장한 바이커들이 모여있는
건물에서 2번의 총질이요?
And shot him twice
in a building occupied
by 15 heavily armed bikers?
더 하기 쉬운 시간과
장소가 있어야해요
I have to believe there were
easier times and places
to do the man in.
러그는 찾았어요?
Has the rug turned up?
아뇨
It has not.
1주일 전에 "사슬톱"이라는 별명의
The bikers in lockup swear
that they got rid of it
a week ago
파티광을 매우 무례한 방법으로
when one of their hard-partying
crew named "Chainsaw,"
땅에 묻을 때 같이 치웠대요
soiled it in
a most unpleasant way.
거짓말 맞죠?
Obviously,
that is a lie, right?
아님 패리스가 러그를 바꿨거나
Or Farris
replaced the rug.
피오나에게 갔던 일은 안 물어봐요?
Aren't you gonna ask me
how it went with Fiona?
피오나와의 일은 어땠어요?
How did it go with Fiona?
잘 됐어요
It went well.
새 상사는 좋은 사람 같아요
Her boss seems like a nice guy.
펜틸리온에 계속 남기로 결정했어요
She's decided
to stay at Pentillion.
피오나를 좋아한다고 말하지 그랬어요
You know, you could have
told me that you like her.
뭐라고 했어요?
I beg your pardon?
당신이 피오나를 좋아하죠
You like her.
네, 피오나 좋아해요
Yes, I like Fiona.
강제적으로 솔직하고
She's compulsively honest,
선천적으로 가식이 없어요
and she's congenitally
unpretentious.
그리고 예쁘죠
And pretty.
무슨 말을 하고 싶어요?
What are you getting at?
'좋아한다'는 의미로 좋아하잖아요
You like her as in like like.
로맨틱한 관심을 뜻하는군요
You're suggesting
a romantic interest,
더 구체적으로는
and more specifically,
you're suggesting
사춘기 이전의 아이들의 말로
a romantic interest
in the vernacular
표현한 로맨틱한 관심이요
of a prepubescent child.
당신이 빌려준 책이죠
This is the book you loaned her.
She wanted me to give
it back to you.
나보고 돌려주래요
그래서요?
So?
그래서
이 집에 수백권의 책이 있는데
시집은 몇권이 있을까요?
Hundreds of books in the house,
how many volumes of poetry?
0권
Zero.
피오나를 위해 샀죠
You bought if for her.
빌려주려고 샀어요
Bought it to lend it.
그래요
Right.
됐어요?
Do you mind?
아뇨. 전혀
No, I don't mind at all.
아, 쫌
Come on.
왜 이렇게 이상하게 굴어요?
Why are you being
so weird about this?
내가 이상하군요
I'm being weird.
네, 그래요
Yes, you are.
다른 사람을 좋아하다니, 놀라운 일이에요
You like someone,
that's amazing.
난 여자 좋아해요
I like many women,
동시에 2명도, 알면서
often two at at time,
you know that.
아니, 섹스 얘기가 아니에요
No, this is not about sex.
진짜 좋아하잖아요
You really like her.
그 단어 좀 그만써요
Stop using that word.
미안해요, 놀려서 미안하지만
I'm sorry,
and I'm sorry that I teased you,
잘된 일이라고 생각해요
but I really do think
this is great.
돕고싶어요
I want to help.
도와요?
Help?
말해요, 피오나에 대한 감정을요
I could talk to her,
feel her out.
서로 마음이 있는지 알아봐요
See if the feeling is mutual.
책은 잘 안됐지만
Look, the book thing
didn't work out,
다른 걸 찾을 수도 있어요
but maybe we could find
something that does.
더닝 형사의 부검 보고서예요
It's Detective Dunning's
autopsy report.
"사인은 다발성 총상"
"Cause of death,
multiple gunshots."
놀랍고, 놀라워요
Surprise, surprise.
왜요?
What?
당장 부검실에 가야겠어요
We need to go to
the morgue right away.
뭘 찾는지 말해줄래요?
Do you want to tell me
what we're looking for?
Iceland.
아이슬란드
"특징"에서
Under "distinguishing marks,"
부검의는 작은 점을 기록했어요
the medical examiner
listed a small mole.
위치는
It's location...
Detective Dunning's right wrist.
더닝 형사의 오른손목이죠
말도 안돼
This doesn't make any sense.
인정하면 돼요
It does, if you let it.
우리가 봤던, 라이언 더닝을 쏜 사람은
The man we saw
shoot Ryan Dunning,
라이언 더닝이었어요
was Ryan Dunning.
더닝과 공범은 영상을 조작했어요
Dunning and
an accomplice staged the video.
공범이 카메라를 차고
Dunning played the part
of the shooter,
더닝이 총격범 역할을 했어요
while his partner
wore the camera.
-이유는?
-우리도 아직 몰라요
- Why?
- Well, we don't know yet.
아마 생존전략으로
죽음을 위장했을 겁니다
Presumably, he intended
to survive the ruse
and merely fake his own death.
신원을 알 수 없게 시체를 훼손하거나
Maybe he was gonna leave us
a body we couldn't identify
카메라만 찾도록 만들려고 했을 거예요
or maybe the camera
was just gonna turn up.
부검실에 있는 유해 상태로 봐선
Given his current residency
at the morgue,
공범이 이중배신을 했던 것 같아요
it seems likely
that his co-conspirator
double-crossed him.
진짜 총상이 우리가 봤다고
믿었던 영상과 일치해요
The real bullet wounds
were positioned to match
what we believe we saw.
적어도 범인은 영상의 조작을
알았다고 보여집니다
At the very least,
this suggests an awareness
on the killer's part
that a video was being made.
점 하나로 다 알아냈군
All this over a mole.
잘못됐을수도 있어
Hell, it could be
a piece of dirt.
단지 점이 아니에요
It isn't just the mole.
손의 주인을 알고 나서
Once we realized
whose hand we were looking at,
영상을 다시 보니
we re-examined the video.
총격범의 다리와 하체가
The shooter's legs
and lower body
더닝과 일치했어요
are also a match for Dunning.
반대로
Conversely,
카메라를 달고 있는 사람은
we found that the person
wearing the camera
더닝이 아니라는 걸 알았어요
could not be Dunning.
형사는 188cm였어요
The detective stood
at six-foot-two.
만났을 때
When I met him,
걸음걸이 폭은 34인치였어요
I measured his stride length
to be 34 inches.
영상의 디테일에 의문을 가진 결과
Upon questioning
those details in the video,
카메라를 단 사람은 170cm,
I estimate the camera's wearer
to be about five-foot-seven,
30인치의 걸음걸이였고
with a step length of 30 inches,
왼다리가 약간 불편해요
also a slight favor
of the left leg.
I know.
알아
받아들일게 많지, 윌
It's a lot to take in, Will.
받아들일게 많다고?
A lot to take in?
믿을수가 없어
It's unbelievable.
왜?
Why?
왜 영상을 조작했지?
Why would he stage the video?
무슨 이득이 있어서?
What did he stand to gain?
더닝이 조폭들을 해산시키기 위해
You told me that Dunning
had been pushing
1년동안 고생했다고 말했잖은가
for months to take
down that crew?
패리스의 방에서
자신의 사망을 조작하다가
Staging his own murder
in Farris' office
-실제로 벌어진거지
-동기는,
- made that happen.
- As for motive,
지금은 가설일 뿐이지만,
at this point,
we can only theorize.
더닝 형사는 진정한 요새 안에서
Detective Dunning managed
to shoot this video
비디오를 찍고 있었어요
inside a veritable fortress.
그런 상황에서
Given those circumstances,
한명 이상의 조폭과
it seems likely he was in league
결탁했을 것으로 보여요
with one or more members
of the gang.
잘 숨겨진 반란이었을 가능성도 있어요
It's possible it was
a well-concealed mutiny.
패리스는 큰 손해를 보고
Farris takes a big fall,
부하들은 질책을 당하고
while his underlings
get slaps on the wrist.
들키기 전에
They get out
long before he does,
더닝의 파트너가 최고의
자리에 오르려고요
and Dunning's partner
rises to the top.
그것도 다른 가능성일 뿐이지
There's another possibility,
too.
더닝의 마지막 임무는
멕시코인들에게 물건을 사는 거였어
Dunning's last assignment
had him buying product
from the Mexicans.
이제 그들이 무혈입성해서
Now they've stepped right
into the vacuum
패리스의 영역을 접수하겠지
and taken over Farris' corners.
아마도
Maybe,
더닝이 그쪽과 사이가 좋아서
Dunning got chummy
with one of them.
강요했을수도 있어
Maybe they coerced him
into doing this,
모르겠어
I-I don't know,
but I'll look into it,
하지만 조사해서
진실이 뭐든 우리가 처리할거야
and whatever the truth is,
we'll deal with it.
누구한테 전화하려고요?
Who are you calling?
CCS.
더닝이 경감에게 조폭 급습을 종용했을 때
Back when
Detective Dunning
was urging his captain
to raid the gang,
패리스의 컴퓨터에 증거가
he insisted
that Farris' computer
가득하다고 주장했어요
held a wealth
of evidence against them.
이제 거짓말로 경감을
낚으려고 했는지
Now, that might
have been a lie
to bait the captain
into action
진실을 말했는지 알 수 있어요
or he might have been
telling the truth.
진실이라면
If it is true,
컴퓨터에는 조폭의 활동과
that computer has
all the details
재정기록이 가득하겠죠
of the gang's
activities and finances.
다른 동기를 찾기에 좋은 곳이죠
A good place to look for other
motives to break them up.
더닝이 컴퓨터에 대해 진실을
말했는지 묻는다면, 진실이에요
If you're asking if Dunning
was telling the truth
about the computer, he was.
암호를 푸는데 시간이 걸려서
It took some time
to break the encryption,
아직 전부 보지는 못했지만
so I haven't been through
the whole machine yet,
이미 많은 자료가 있고
but there's already plenty here,
단지 패리스에 대한 증거만은 아니에요
and not just against Farris.
중서부의 공급자들도 많이
걱정해야한다는 말이죠
I'd say his suppliers
in the Midwest
have plenty to worry about, too.
돈은요? 더닝이
은행기록도 언급했는데
What about money? Dunning
mentioned banking records.
네, 패리스는 스위스와
케이먼군도에 계좌가 있어요
Yes, Farris had accounts
in Switzerland,
and the Cayman Islands.
Would you be able to tell
지난 24시간동안 이 계좌들에
움직임이 있는지 말해줄 수 있어요?
if there was any activity
on these accounts
in the last 24 hours?
확인했어요
I checked.
어제 오전에 누군가 없애려고 했어요
Someone cleaned them out
late yesterday morning.
총 5.5억달러였어요
All together, about
five-and-a-half million dollars.
The transfers were
at around 11:30.
11시30분경 이체됐어요
급습 직후이고
That was after the raid,
경찰이 패리스를 잡기 전이어서
and before police
picked up Farris,
우리가 컴퓨터를 가진 걸 알고
so it's possible he realized
we had his computer,
돈을 빼냈을 수도 있어요
and moved the money
while he still could.
아님 더닝의 공범이
경찰의 급습을 이용해
Or Dunning's accomplice
used the distraction
of a police raid
패리스의 돈을 가졌을 수도 있어요
to help himself
to Farris' money.
Excuse me a minute--
this is my captain.
실례해요. 우리 보스네요
당신이 맞았어요
You were right.
-뭐가요?
-피오나요
About?
About Fiona.
피오나에게 끌렸어요
I am drawn to her.
You say that like
it's a bad thing.
나쁜 일인것처럼 말하네요
-나쁜 일이죠
-왜요?
It is a bad thing.
Why?
내 기분대로 행동해서
Well, let's say
I acted on my feelings.
사귄다고 쳐요
and I, engaged her.
관계를 구속하겠죠
Forged a relationship.
피오나를 위해 잘 끝내겠다?
Do you think
that would end well for her?
왜 헤어질 생각부터 해요?
Why are you assuming
it would end?
아, 피오나가 내 운명이라서요?
So she's my destiny now,
is she?
결혼해서 아이라도 가질까요
We're going to get married
and have children.
내 말은, 데이트도 안했으면서
I'm just saying, you're worrying
about the breakup
헤어질 걱정부터 하잖아요
when you haven't even
gone out on a date.
-데이트는 하지 않아요
-왜요?
There's not going to be a date.
Why not?
보통 여자들보다 더 예민하니까요
Because she's more sensitive
than the average woman.
쉽게 상처받고 혼란스러워해요
She's easier
to hurt and confuse.
상처주지 말아요,
혼란스럽게 하지도 말고
So, don't hurt her.
Don't confuse her.
난 모두를 혼란스럽게해요
I confuse everyone.
피오나에게 데이트신청을 하지 않음으로서
So, by not asking Fiona out,
당신에게서 피오나를 보호하는군요
you are protecting her from you.
That is ridiculous.
헛소리예요
당신은 관계를 만들지
못하는 것처럼 말하지만
You make it sound like you
can't be in a relationship,
했잖아요. 아이린과
when you were, with Irene.
아, 모리아티 말이군요?
You mean Moriarty?
뭐라고 부르든
Whatever you want
to call her,
사랑했잖아요
you loved her.
당신의 마음을 찢어놨죠, 알아요
She broke your heart,
I get it,
하지만 아이린이 그랬다고
but just because she did,
피오나도 그럴거라는 뜻은 아니에요
doesn't mean
that Fiona will, too.
미안해요
Sorry...
전 녹취준비를 해야하지만
I have to go prep a deposition,
증거는 계속 봐도 돼요
but you can keep all of this.
다른 걸 발견하면 알려드릴게요
I'll let you know
if I find anything else.
고마워요
Okay, thanks.
멋진 엉덩이죠, 알아요
She has a nice butt, okay.
그만 봐요
You don't have to stare at it.
Detective Hagen?
헤이건 형사?
미안한데 우리 경감님이 찾아요
Sorry, our captain would
like a quick word.
얼마 안 걸린대요
It shouldn't take a moment.
네
Okay.
Thanks.
고마워요
경감님 안 계실텐데
Captain's not even here.
형사 키가 얼마로 보여요?
How tall would you say
the detective was?
글쎄요, 170?
I don't know, five-seven?
왼다리는 어때요?
See how she favors
her left leg?
She has a step length
of approximately 30 inches,
걸음폭은 30인치정도
동의하지 않아요?
or wouldn't you agree?
저 걸음걸이 본 적 있어요
We've seen that gait before.
Detective Hagen was
Ryan Dunning's accomplice.
헤이건 형사가 라이언 더닝의 공범이었어요
저 영상에서 더닝 역할을 했어요
She plays the part
of Dunning in that video.
왜?
Why?
엉덩이와 가슴 때문이죠
She has hips and breasts.
카메라 뒤에 숨어서 신분을 숨겼어요
Putting her behind the camera
protects her identity.
둘의 공모는 말할 것도 없고
Not to mention the fact that
in this conspiracy of two,
더닝은 조폭들을 속여야했어요
only Dunning could pass
for a member of the Brood.
컴퓨터 때문이었어요
This was about the computer.
계속 컴퓨터 때문이었죠
This was always
about the computer.
암호를 풀 시간을 충분히 얻어서
Gaining access to it long enough
to decrypt its contents
닉 패리스의 은행 계좌를 털기 위해서
and empty Nick Farris'
bank accounts.
더닝은 조폭 근거지에 급습하도록
Dunning spent months trying
to convince his captain
확신을 주기 위해 1년을 공들였어요
to execute a raid
on the gang's headquarters.
급습에 따라오는 게 뭘까요?
What would said raid
have accomplished?
리사 헤이건의 손에 컴퓨터가 들어가죠
It would put the computer
in Lisa Hagen's hands.
정확해요
Precisely.
롬바르디 경감이 급습을 거부하자
Only Captain Lombardi
refuses to act,
두 형사는 플랜B를 만들어냈어요
so the two detectives
concoct Plan B.
더닝의 죽음을 위조해서
급습을 재촉했죠
Fake Dunning's murder
to force the raid.
같은 결과
Same result.
컴퓨터는 헤이건에게로
Computer goes to Hagen.
이번에는 보너스가 추가돼요
Only this time,
she gets an added bonus,
두배로
doubling the value of her prize.
더닝을 죽여서
돈을 혼자 차지했어요
She kills Dunning,
keeps all the money for herself.
You're right.
맞아요
Everything you're saying
fits perfectly.
당신 말이 전부 딱 맞아요
고마워요
Thank you.
하나만 빼면
Except for one thing,
하나도 성립이 되지 않아요
none of it makes any sense.
Dunning shows up
at a heavily guarded building
더닝이 중무장 건물에 다른 경찰,
여자경찰을 데리고 나타나면
with a second cop, a female cop,
쉽게 눈에 띄었을 거예요
which you would think
would stand out a little.
바이커들을 피해
몰래 방으로 들어가서
Somehow he sneaks
past a gauntlet of bikers
into the office,
총성이 들리는 영상을 찍고
where they stay long enough
to shoot a video,
with gunshots,
and then get out alive.
살아서 나왔다
더닝이 어떻게 혼자
들어가서 파일을 저장할
Have you forgotten about
the hours you spent trying
to figure out how to get Dunning
in there alone,
시간을 가진 다음에 빠져나왔는지
고민했던 시간들을 잊었어요?
just to give him enough time
to copy files to a stick drive?
Um, can you remind me,
다시 말해봐요
누가 더닝이고 누가 헤이건이죠?
which one of these is Dunning,
and which one is Hagen?
아, 상관없죠
Right,
it doesn't matter,
둘다 죽었을테니까
because they would both be dead.
롬바르디 경감에 따르면
According to Captain Lombardi,
리사 헤이건과 라이언 더닝은
예전 임무에서 같이 일했어요
Lisa Hagen and Ryan Dunning
worked together
on a previous assignment.
친했을 거예요
Perhaps they grew close.
무척 친해졌겠죠
Perhaps they grew very close.
패리스의 컴퓨터 암호 때문에
Given the encryption
on Farris' computer,
더닝은 데이터를 캐낼 전문가가
필요하다는 걸 알았어요
Dunning would have known he'd
need an expert to mine its data.
내 질문으로 돌아가도
Which brings us back
to my question,
아직 대답을 못했잖아요
which you still
haven't answered.
더닝이 컴퓨터 전문가를 데리고
If Dunning could get
a computer expert in,
들어갈 시간이 충분했다면
and with all that time,
왜 컴퓨터를 가지고 나와야했을까요?
why would he need
to get the computer out,
그냥 복사를 하지 않고
Why not just copy the files?
파일 복사를 막는 안전장치를 걸어놨다면
Perhaps Farris'
safeguards prevented one
from simply copying the files.
그렇다면, 컴퓨터를 가지고 나와서
If so, getting the computer
out of the office
경찰 연구실에 가져올 필요가 있죠
and into the police lab would
still have been necessary.
그렇다고 해도, 아직도 모르는게
Okay, even if you're right,
which, I'm still not saying,
어떻게 증명하죠?
how are we going to prove it?
계좌이체는 추적이 불가능하고
The bank transfers
are untraceable,
리사는 이틀동안 그 컴퓨터에
대해 전권을 위임받았어요
and Lisa's
had carte Blanche
to that computer
for at least two days.
남겨놨을 디지털 흔적을
I mean, she would
have been smart enough
to get rid
of any digital track
모두 없앨 정도로 똑똑하겠죠
she might have left.
자 이제
Okay, now,
당신은 안 자더라도, 난 잘거니까
you might not need sleep,
but I do,
내 방에서 나가요
so please, get out of my room.
I know it's late,
but I wanted to give Joan
늦은 시간인 줄은 알지만 조앤에게
감사선물을 주고 싶었어요
a present for helping me.
오, 들어와요
Come in.
음식은 새 집이나
아기를 위한 선물이지만
Food is for new houses
or babies,
이건 파이고, 후식이죠
but this is pie,
which is for dessert.
와인은 디너 파티를 위한 선물,
Wine is
for dinner parties.
꽃은 색에 따라서
여러가지 의미가 있어요
Flowers can be
lots of things,
I guess,
depending on the color.
이건 노란색, 여러가지 목적이 있지만
These are yellow,
multi-purpose,
로맨틱하지는 않아요
but not romantic.
원하는 선물을 골라도 되고
She can pick
the gift she wants,
or have them all.
전부 가져도 돼요
Is she here?
조앤은 집에 있어요?
네, 자려고 들어갔지만
Yes, she's just
turning in for the night,
잠깐 시간을 주면
but if you
give me a moment...
아니, 괜찮아요
No, that's okay.
방해하고 싶지 않아요
I don't want
to bother her.
And besides,
그리고
I also wanted to see you.
난 당신도 만나고 싶었어요
필이 체포되던 날,
당신이 집에 와서
The day Phil was arrested,
you walked me home.
우리 얘기했어요, 좋았어요
We talked...
and I liked it...
...talking to you.
당신과의 대화가요
다시 할 수 있어요?
Can we do it again?
It's pretty up here.
여기 예뻐요
My apartment has
a nice view,
내 아파트도 전망이 좋지만
이정도는 아니에요
but nothing like this.
필 발삼을 대신해서 오는
상사와 일한다고 들었어요
Watson tells me you're
about to start working
with Phil Balsam's
replacement.
Next week.
다음주예요
이름은 그렉 와키노에요
His name is Greg Wakino.
I, I wrote him
an e-mail today.
오늘 이메일을 보냈어요
I explained
that I'm neuro-atypical.
내가 neuro-atypical이라고 설명했어요
나와 일하는 게 어떨지,
내가 그에게 원하는 것,
Told him
what it's like
to work with me,
그가 예상할 수 있는 걸 말했어요
what I need from him,
and what he can expect.
우리가 만났을 때 더 쉬워지겠죠
That way when we meet,
it'll be easier.
그도 고마워할 겁니다
I'm sure
he appreciated that.
It's hard for me, talking,
난 다른 사람들처럼 가려서
말하는 게 힘들어요
not picking up on the things
that other people do.
지금같은
The the signals...
분위기에서
...like now.
날 만나서 좋은건지 모르겠어요
I can't tell if you're,
if you're happy to see me, or...
만나서 정말 좋아요
I'm very happy to see you.
나한테 키스해줄래요?
Would you like to kiss me?
나도 당신이 좋아서 묻는 거예요
Asking 'cause I'd like you to.
Um, Fiona...
피오나
당신 생각을 했어요
I've been,
thinking about you.
Spending time with you that day,
그날 같이 있었을 때
즐거웠어요
I enjoyed it.
그런 적이 드물어요
That doesn't happen very often.
Also, you're very handsome,
당신은 잘생기고
냄새가 좋아요
and you smell nice.
대부분은 그렇지 않아요
A lot of people don't.
Was that your phone?
당신 전화였죠?
Yes it was.
네, 맞아요
확인 안하는 게 이상해요
Strange that you're
not checking it, isn't it?
동료인데, 전화해달래요
It's a colleague,
he wants me to call him.
난 갈게요
I'll go now.
가지말아요
You don't have to.
갈래요
I should.
여기 와서 이 말을 하는 건
This was hard, coming here,
힘들었어요
saying these things.
말해서 기쁘지만,
이제 그만할래요
I'm glad I did,
but I'd like to stop now.
셜록!
Sherlock!
이게 다 뭐예요?
What the hell is all this?
혼란스럽죠
You're confused.
깨우지 않고 어떻게 당신과 침대를
You're wondering
how I managed to move you
미디어룸으로 옮겼는지 궁금하죠
and your bed to the media room
without waking you.
-조금요
-내가 옮기지 않았어요
A little.
I didn't move you.
다른 사람이 했다는 말이에요?
Wh-- are you saying
someone else did?
어제 당신이 들어가고 나서
마커스가 러그를 찾았다고 했어요
After you turned in last night,
Marcus informed me
that the missing rug
had been found.
영상에 있던 러그요?
The one from the video?
쓰레기 매립지에서
경찰이 찾았어요
The police traced it
from the gang's Dumpster
to a landfill.
바이커들이 말했던
그대로 묻혀있었어요
It had been soiled
in precisely the way
the bikers said it would be.
그래서요?
So?
조작된 영상에서는 더럽지 않아요
So, it was not soiled
in the staged video.
내 침대를 여기로 옮긴 이유가 이거예요?
What does this have to do
with you
moving my bed in here?
말했듯이, 옮기지 않았어요
As I said, I didn't move you.
창문 밖을 봐요, 당신은
2층에 그대로 있어요
Look out the window,
you'll see you're still
squarely on the second floor.
여긴 내 침실이군요
This is my bedroom.
내가 미디어룸에 있다고 생각하도록
So, you moved all
this stuff down here
만들려고 이걸 다 옮겼어요
to make me think
I was in the media room.
이제 두 러그가 같아보이지
않는 이유를 알겠죠
Now you know why the two rugs
don't look the same.
하나는 진짜였고
One of them
is the genuine article...
하나는 소품이죠
And the other's a prop.
더닝과 헤이건은 다른 곳에
So Dunning and Hagen
built an exact replica
사무실을 그대로 복제해서
of this office someplace else.
영상을 찍었어요
That's where they
shot the video.
찾기는 쉬워요. 그렇죠?
I'd very much like to find it,
wouldn't you?
들어주지 않아도 돼요
You don't have to carry that.
난 형사예요
I'm a big detective.
아뇨, 제가 들고싶어요
No, it's my pleasure.
만나서 기뻐요
So glad we ran
into each other,
이전 만남이 얼마나 도움이
됐는지 말할 기회가 생겨서요
it gives me a chance
to tell you
how useful
our previous meeting was.
잘됐네요
Glad to hear it.
패리스의 컴퓨터 전체를 복원해서
I think that's everything
off Farris' computer now,
더 자세한 보고서를 줄 수 있어요
so I can give you
a more thorough report.
녹취는 어땠어요?
How was your deposition?
다음주로 재조정됐어요
Rescheduled for next week.
물어볼게요
I just have to ask,
옆에서 우리가 가져온 잡동사니들로
the bits and pieces
we get from the sidelines,
반쯤 맞춘 직소퍼즐을 같이 푸는 것 같아요
it's like trying to put
a jigsaw puzzle together
with half the set.
좋은 경험이었어요,
경험해보지 않았다면
Good practice, by the way,
if you haven't tried it.
더닝이 은행 계좌를 얻으려고
Um, I-I heard Dunning
faked his own murder
자기 죽음을 위장했다고 들었는데
to get to the bank accounts,
정말 공범이 죽였어요?
but then his accomplice
really killed him?
그렇게 보여요
That's our understanding.
더 빨리 알아야해요
We should know
more soon, yeah.
아, 오늘은 이쪽이에요
We're in here today.
열어줄래요?
Would you mind?
형사, 앉아요
Detective, have a seat.
헤이건 형사
Detective Hagen.
노조 대표인 리바 형사야
This is Detective Riba,
your union delegate.
당신이 한 짓을 알아요, 리사
We know you did it, Lisa.
고백할게요
I confess,
꽤 애먹었어요
we were stumped
for quite some time,
당신과 더닝 형사가 영상을
찍은 방법을 알아내느라
trying to work out how you
and Detective Dunning
shot that video.
그러다가 촬영장소를
알아야한다는 걸 깨달았어요
Then we realized
it was more a question
of where you shot it.
닉 패리스의 방을 그대로
복제했다는 걸 이해했어요
Once we understood
that you had created
a facsimile
of Nick Farris' office,
장소가 문제였죠
it was just a matter
of locating it.
조부모님이 태리타운에서
앤티크 사업을 했죠
Your grandparents were in
the antiques business
up in Tarrytown.
가족 소유의 창고가
있다는 걸 알았어요
We saw that your family
still owns a warehouse up there.
오늘 아침 수색을 해서
We searched it this morning,
세트장의 일부를 발견했어요
and found what's left
of your set.
옷도 완벽했고
You dressed it perfectly.
모든 디테일이 완벽했어요
Meticulously matching
every detail.
판넬 벽,
Paneled walls,
책상, 여자 달력,
desk, girlie calendar...
러그
the rug.
촬영이 끝났을 때
At some point
after you were done,
당신이 뒤에서
더닝을 진짜로 쐈어요
you shot Dunning
in the back for real.
영상과 똑같은 각도에서 신중하게,
You were careful to use
the same angles
as you did in the video,
so they would match,
머리에 마지막 총알을
쏘는 것도 잊지 않고
including the final shot
to the head.
전부 청소도 잘했어요
You did your best
to scrub everything down.
씻을 수 없는 건 태웠어요
Burned what you
couldn't wash away.
하지만 가짜 현장과
실제 사무실은 달랐어요
But that's the difference
between a fake crime scene
and a real one.
증거가 항상 따라붙어요
Evidence always
sticks around.
이 대화를 위해 노조대표를
부르지 말았어야했어
We didn't have to invite
your union delegate
for this conversation.
급습할 수도 있었어
We could have ambushed you,
자네가 더닝 형사에게 했던 대로
like you ambushed
Detective Dunning.
하지만 결국
But in the end,
경찰로 존중해서 처리하기로 했어
we decided
to treat you with respect,
like a cop.
우리가 모르는 건,
Really, the only
things we don't know,
작은 자비를 보여주길 바라는데,
and-and this might offer you
some small saving grace,
처음에는 누구의 아이디어였는지
is who's idea it was
in the first place,
언제 계획을 바꿔서
and when the plan changed,
더닝 형사를 죽이기로 했죠?
leading to
Detective Dunning's death.
당신을 폭행했을 수도 있고
Maybe he got
violent with you,
더닝의 배신을 먼저 알고
and maybe you realized
he was gonna
죽였을 수도 있어요
double-cross you,
so you killed him first.
쉽게 말해준다면 좋을거야
If there's anything
you want to tell us
to make this go easier,
now's your chance.
이제 자네 선택이야
I was hoping we might resume our
conversation from last night.
어젯밤의 대화를 다시
시작했으면 좋겠어요
들어와요
Come in.
??Hey, hey, take me,
I'm yours... ??
예전에 사귄 남자친구들이 있었어요
I've had boyfriends before.
I, myself, have not.
난, 없어요
적절한 남자를 만나지
못했을 수도 있지만
Perhaps I just haven't met
the right guy.
궁금해할 거라고 생각했어요
I thought maybe you
were wondering...
if...
가끔 놀라는 사람들도 있어요
I don't know--
sometimes people are surprised.
당신은 뛰어난 여자예요
You're a remarkable woman.
I assumed I was not
the first person to notice that.
그걸 알아본 사람이
내가 처음은 아니겠죠
난 당신이 데이트를 했던 여자들이나
I'm different, too,
from other women you've dated,
했을지도 모르는 여자들과 다르기도 해요
or other women you could date.
나와 사귀는 건 더 힘들고
It takes a little
more work with me.
시간이 더 걸려요
A little more time.
사귀었던 2명의 남자친구에게
I know that
because I've heard it
들어서 알고 있어요
from both
my previous boyfriends.
그들은 NT, neuro-typical이었어요
They were NT, neuro-typical.
개인적으로, 전형적인 걸 싫어해요
Personally, I abhor the typical.
??Hey, hey, baby... ??
Does the offer
to kiss you still stand?
키스해달라는 제안, 아직 유효해요?
아뇨
No.
유효하기는 하지만
I mean it does,
지금 당장은 아니에요
just not right now.
??Let me in... ??
약간 떨려요
I'm a little afraid.
??Hey, hey, baby... ??
나도 약간 떨려요
I'm a little afraid, too.
커피 마실까요?
Would you like to get
some coffee with me?
아주 좋아요
I'd be delighted.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man